<class category="Core" inherits="Joint2D" name="DampedSpringJoint2D"><brief_description>
		Damped spring constraint for 2D physics.</brief_description><description>
		Damped spring constraint for 2D physics. This resembles a spring joint that always wants to go back to a given length.</description><methods><method name="get_damping" qualifiers="const"><return type="float"></return><description>
				Return the damping ratio of the spring joint. A value of 0 indicates an undamped spring, while 1 causes the system to reach equilibrium as fast as possible (critical damping).</description></method><method name="get_length" qualifiers="const"><return type="float"></return><description>
				Return the maximum length of the spring joint.</description></method><method name="get_rest_length" qualifiers="const"><return type="float"></return><description>
				Return the resting length of the spring joint. The joint will always try to go to back this length when pulled apart.</description></method><method name="get_stiffness" qualifiers="const"><return type="float"></return><description>
				Return the stiffness of the spring joint. The joint applies a force equal to the stiffness times the distance from its resting length.</description></method><method name="set_damping"><argument index="0" name="damping" type="float"></argument><description>
				Set the damping ratio of the spring joint. A value of 0 indicates an undamped spring, while 1 causes the system to reach equilibrium as fast as possible (critical damping).</description></method><method name="set_length"><argument index="0" name="length" type="float"></argument><description>
				Set the maximum length of the spring joint.</description></method><method name="set_rest_length"><argument index="0" name="rest_length" type="float"></argument><description>
				Set the resting length of the spring joint. The joint will always try to go to back this length when pulled apart.</description></method><method name="set_stiffness"><argument index="0" name="stiffness" type="float"></argument><description>
				Set the stiffness of the spring joint. The joint applies a force equal to the stiffness times the distance from its resting length.</description></method></methods><constants></constants></class>