<class name="KinematicBody2D" inherits="PhysicsBody2D" category="Core"><brief_description>Kinematic body 2D node.
</brief_description><description>Kinematic bodies are special types of bodies that are meant to be user-controlled. They are not affected by physics at all (to other types of bodies, such a character or a rigid body, these are the same as a static body). They have however, two main uses:
Simulated Motion: When these bodies are moved manually, either from code or from an AnimationPlayer (with process mode set to fixed), the physics will automatically compute an estimate of their linear and angular velocity. This makes them very useful for moving platforms or other AnimationPlayer-controlled objects (like a door, a bridge that opens, etc).
Kinematic Characters: KinematicBody2D also has an api for moving objects (the [method move] method) while performing collision tests. This makes them really useful to implement characters that collide against a world, but that don't require advanced physics.
</description><methods><method name="get_collider" qualifiers="const"><return type="Variant"></return><description>Return the body that collided with this one.
</description></method><method name="get_collider_metadata" qualifiers="const"><return type="Variant"></return><description>Return the metadata of the shape that collided with this body. If there is no collision, it will return 0, so collisions must be checked first with [method is_colliding]. Additionally, this metadata can not be set with [method Object.set_meta], it must be set with [method Physics2DServer.body_set_shape_metadata].
</description></method><method name="get_collider_shape" qualifiers="const"><return type="int"></return><description>Return the shape index from the body that collided with this one. If there is no collision, this method will return 0, so collisions must be checked first with [method is_colliding].
</description></method><method name="get_collider_velocity" qualifiers="const"><return type="Vector2"></return><description>Return the velocity of the body that collided with this one.
</description></method><method name="get_collision_margin" qualifiers="const"><return type="float"></return><description>Return the collision margin for this object.
</description></method><method name="get_collision_normal" qualifiers="const"><return type="Vector2"></return><description>Return the normal of the surface the body collided with. This is useful to implement sliding along a surface.
</description></method><method name="get_collision_pos" qualifiers="const"><return type="Vector2"></return><description>Return the point in space where the body is touching another. If there is no collision, this method will return (0,0), so collisions must be checked first with [method is_colliding].
</description></method><method name="get_move_and_slide_colliders" qualifiers="const"><return type="Array"></return><description></description></method><method name="get_travel" qualifiers="const"><return type="Vector2"></return><description>Return the last movement done by the body.
</description></method><method name="is_colliding" qualifiers="const"><return type="bool"></return><description>Return whether the body is colliding with another.
</description></method><method name="is_move_and_slide_on_ceiling" qualifiers="const"><return type="bool"></return><description></description></method><method name="is_move_and_slide_on_floor" qualifiers="const"><return type="bool"></return><description></description></method><method name="is_move_and_slide_on_wall" qualifiers="const"><return type="bool"></return><description></description></method><method name="move"><return type="Vector2"></return><argument index="0" name="rel_vec" type="Vector2"></argument><description>Move the body in the given direction, stopping if there is an obstacle. The returned vector is how much movement was remaining before being stopped.
</description></method><method name="move_and_slide"><return type="Vector2"></return><argument index="0" name="linear_velocity" type="Vector2"></argument><argument index="1" name="floor_normal" type="Vector2" default="Vector2(0, 0)"></argument><argument index="2" name="slope_stop_min_velocity" type="float" default="5"></argument><argument index="3" name="max_bounces" type="int" default="4"></argument><argument index="4" name="floor_max_angle" type="float" default="0.785398"></argument><description></description></method><method name="move_to"><return type="Vector2"></return><argument index="0" name="position" type="Vector2"></argument><description>Move the body to the given position. This is not a teleport, and the body will stop if there is an obstacle. The returned vector is how much movement was remaining before being stopped.
</description></method><method name="revert_motion"><description>Undo the last movement done by the body.
</description></method><method name="set_collision_margin"><argument index="0" name="pixels" type="float"></argument><description>Set the collision margin for this object. A collision margin is an amount (in pixels) that all shapes will grow when computing collisions, to account for numerical imprecision.
</description></method><method name="test_move"><return type="bool"></return><argument index="0" name="rel_vec" type="Vector2"></argument><description>Return true if there would be a collision if the body moved in the given direction.
</description></method><method name="test_move_from"><return type="bool"></return><argument index="0" name="from" type="Matrix32"></argument><argument index="1" name="rel_vec" type="Vector2"></argument><description></description></method></methods><constants></constants></class>