<class name="CollisionPolygon2D" inherits="Node2D" category="Core"><brief_description>Editor-only class for easy editing of collision polygons.
</brief_description><description>Editor-only class. This is not present when running the game. It's used in the editor to properly edit and position collision shapes in [CollisionObject2D]. This is not accessible from regular code. This class is for editing custom shape polygons.
</description><methods><method name="get_build_mode" qualifiers="const"><return type="int"></return><description>Return whether the polygon is a [ConvexPolygonShape2D] ([code]build_mode==0[/code]), or a [ConcavePolygonShape2D] ([code]build_mode==1[/code]).
</description></method><method name="get_collision_object_first_shape" qualifiers="const"><return type="int"></return><description>Return the index of the first shape generated by the editor.
When [code]build_mode[/code] is set to generate convex polygons, the shape shown in the editor may be decomposed into many convex polygons. In that case, a range of indexes is needed to directly access the [Shape2D].
When [code]build_mode[/code] is set to generate concave polygons, there is only one [Shape2D] generated, so the start index and the end index are the same.
</description></method><method name="get_collision_object_last_shape" qualifiers="const"><return type="int"></return><description>Return the index of the last shape generated by the editor.
</description></method><method name="get_polygon" qualifiers="const"><return type="Vector2Array"></return><description>Return the list of points that define the polygon.
</description></method><method name="is_trigger" qualifiers="const"><return type="bool"></return><description>Return whether this polygon is a trigger.
</description></method><method name="set_build_mode"><argument index="0" name="build_mode" type="int"></argument><description>Set whether the polygon is to be a [ConvexPolygonShape2D] ([code]build_mode==0[/code]), or a [ConcavePolygonShape2D] ([code]build_mode==1[/code]).
</description></method><method name="set_polygon"><argument index="0" name="polygon" type="Vector2Array"></argument><description>Set the array of points forming the polygon.
When editing the point list via the editor, depending on [method get_build_mode], it has to be a list of points (for [code]build_mode==0[/code]), or a list of lines (for [code]build_mode==1[/code]). In the second case, the even elements of the array define the start point of the line, and the odd elements the end point.
</description></method><method name="set_trigger"><argument index="0" name="trigger" type="bool"></argument><description>Set whether this polygon is a trigger. A trigger polygon detects collisions, but is otherwise unaffected by physics (i.e. colliding objects will not get blocked).
</description></method></methods><constants></constants></class>